<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Arcvjs&#39;s blog</title>
        <link>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Arcvjs&#39;s blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 11:00:04 &#43;0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Proxy Server</title>
    <link>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/networking/proxy-server/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 11:00:04 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>James S</author>
    <guid>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/networking/proxy-server/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[How to isntall &amp; do simple configuration of Squid&rsquo;s Proxy server on linux Installing squid sudo apt update -y &amp;&amp; sudo apt install squid first we install the squid proxy application. and all of its dependencies.
Configuring the proxy server the configuration file is located in /etc/squid/squid.conf we can edit it using nano
sudo nano /etc/squid/squid.conf now we need to allow http, as the default configuration forbid it.
http_access allow all change deny to allow.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>DNS Server konfigurasi menggunakan bind9</title>
    <link>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/networking/dns-server/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 08:12:20 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>James S</author>
    <guid>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/networking/dns-server/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Tutorial konfigurasi dns server di linux installl bind9 untuk installasi bind9 server di linux gunakan command ini:
sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install bind9 Konfigurasi pertama2 ubah dan buat file named.conf.local:
sudo nano /etc/bind/named.conf.local isi file dengan:
zone &quot;james.com&quot; { type master; file &quot;/etc/bind/db.james.com&quot;; # Path to the zone file }; ubah james.com dengan domain yang kita mau.
sekarang kita buat file db.james.com
sesuaikan dengan apa yang ditulis di named.conf.local]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>DHCP Server configuration di linux</title>
    <link>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/networking/dhcp-server/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 08:12:15 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>James S</author>
    <guid>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/networking/dhcp-server/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Cara konfigurasi DHCP Server di linux dalam tutorial ini, saya akan menjelaskan cara konfigurasi dchp server di debian linux. Saaya akan menggunakan isc-dhcp-server.
Installasi isc-dhcp-server Untuk menginstall isc-dhcp-server, saya akan menggunakan apt:
sudo apt-get update sudo apt-uget install isc-dhcp-server Konfigurasi gunakan command ini untuk mengubah file konfigurasi:
sudo nano /etc/dhcp/dhcpd.conf berikut contoh konfigurasi
subnet 192.168.1.0 netmask 255.255.255.0 { range 192.168.1.100 192.168.1.200; option routers 192.168.1.1; option domain-name-servers 8.8.8.8, 8.8.4.4; option subnet-mask 255.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>FTP Server configuration</title>
    <link>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/networking/ftp-server/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 07:50:37 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>James S</author>
    <guid>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/networking/ftp-server/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[#How to configure vsftpd server in debian Dalam tutorial ini saya akan menjelaskan cara konfigurasi vsftpd. u
Installasi vsftpd server Untuk menginstallasi vsftpd di linux, dapat menggunakan package manager apt-get, menggunakan command seperti dibawah ini:
sudo apt-get install vsftpd Ubah file konfigurasi vsftpd Setelah vsftpd sudah terinstall tanpa error, selanjutnya kita ubah file konfigurasi default di linux. Kita akan menggunakan text editor nano:
sudo nano /etc/vsftpd.conf Masukan password karena perlu privilages sudo.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>SSH Config Debian</title>
    <link>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/networking/ssh-config/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 09:57:44 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>James S</author>
    <guid>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/networking/ssh-config/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[#Configurasi SSH di Linux
Update dan Upgrade repository gunakan command apt untuk mengupdate and upgrade package yang sudah terinstall, sebagai best practice. jalankan perintah berikut di terminal linux anda.
sudo apt update &amp;&amp; sudo apt upgrade Install openssh-server gunakan apt package manager untuk menginstall openssh-server, jalankan perintah dibawah:
sudo apt install openssh-server -y flag -y digunakan untuk menerima konfirmasi installasi (tidak wajib).
Jalankan sshd service setiap boot gunakan command systemctl untuk membuat sshd berjalan setiap linux di booting, jalankan perintah dibawah ini:]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Static Aint Always Noise</title>
    <link>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/picogym/static-aint-always-noise/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 21:05:19 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>James S</author>
    <guid>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/picogym/static-aint-always-noise/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Static Ain&rsquo;t Always Noise Picogym writeups. we we&rsquo;re given two files. static and ltdis.sh . static is filled with binary data. so i tried to print all readables character in it with the command string. and after a little bit of scrolling i found the flag.
use the command:
strings static | grep pico{ flag: picoCTF{d15a5m_t34s3r_f6c48608}]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Mind Your Ps and Qs</title>
    <link>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/picogym/mind-your-ps-and-qs/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 10:45:34 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>James S</author>
    <guid>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/picogym/mind-your-ps-and-qs/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Mind Your Ps and Qs picoGym writeup. Challenges In RSA, a small e value can be problematic, but what about N? Can you decrypt this?
File given: values
values: c= 8533139361076999596208540806559574687666062896040360148742851107661304651861689 n= 769457290801263793712740792519696786147248001937382943813345728685422050738403253 e= 65537 Explaination RSA is an asymmetric cryptographic algorithm. It is called asymmetric because there are 2 keys. Public key are used to encrypt the clear text. Private key on the other hand are used to decrypt the encrypted text.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Information</title>
    <link>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/picogym/information/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 20:38:18 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>James S</author>
    <guid>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/picogym/information/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Information Picogym Writeups Files can always be changed in a secret way. Can you find the flag?
We were given the file cat.jpg. There&rsquo;s something called a metadata on some images. Metadata stores basic information about the images. Such as author, time when the picture was taken, color profiles, and many more.
To view the metadata of an images, you can use a tool called exiftool. To install it on Ubuntu or other Debian based system you can use the command: sudo apt install exiftool Or if you are on a arch based system you can use the command: sudo pacman -S perl-image-exiftool Alternatively you can use an online tool to view metadatas.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Pickle Rick TryHackMe Writeup</title>
    <link>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/tryhackme/pickle-rick-tryhackme-writeup/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 22:49:54 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>James S</author>
    <guid>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/tryhackme/pickle-rick-tryhackme-writeup/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Pickle Rick TryHackMe Writeup This is a blog on how i solved Pickle Rick room on tryhackme. Note that i use linux. First i put the machine IP into env using the export command.
export IP=(your target machine&#39;s IP addres) Enum Nmap I did a simple nmap scan on the server:
nmap -sCV -oN nmap-init.log $IP -sCV is for using the default scripts and check for services version on the machine.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Postman CryptoburstCTF 2022 writeup</title>
    <link>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/ctf/cryptoburst/postman/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 09:46:34 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>James S</author>
    <guid>https://arcvjs.github.io/posts/ctf/cryptoburst/postman/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Postman - cryptoburst ctf 2022 writeups we were given the image first i tried searching for postman qr. Found no result. then, i tried reverse searching with google images. i found a similar images, from a website explaining types of barcode. https://www.dynamsoft.com/blog/insights/the-comprehensive-guide-to-1d-and-2d-barcodes/ the name of the barcodes are MaxiCode. It was used by UPS so the name Postman makes sense. Now it just comes down to reading the qr. After some browsing i found an online tool for reading.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
